{
    "id": "bc530b2719f04cb69676e3b19bd25782",
    "title": "Simple Past Vs. Present Perfect Tense",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "He ………………………… born in",
            "description": "Use the simple past to talk about the year in which people were born.",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "has been",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "8114a3fd3bdc4dd9849977a0da3b0884"
        },
        {
            "question": "She …………………………….. any interest in politics.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "never showed",
                "has never showed",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "c6adbf5f8e9d40648490eb0f0046fb7a"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………….. all of my friends to my party.",
            "description": "In British English, the present perfect is common here. ",
            "answers": [
                "invited",
                "have invited",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "f91964f5524b4318b18e7cf3c47ff3be"
        },
        {
            "question": "None of my friends …………………………. up for my party.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "turned",
                "has turned",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "8cbccedec5924332a769a609370f236b"
        },
        {
            "question": "My grandmother …………………………… at the age of",
            "description": "Use the simple past to talk about a completely finished event. ",
            "answers": [
                "died",
                "has died",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "4d6a941c372549f591f2adaec60aa66d"
        },
        {
            "question": "She ………………………… last month after a prolonged battle against cancer.",
            "description": "You cannot use the present perfect with past time expressions like last month. ",
            "answers": [
                "died",
                "has died",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "cba82fad675547f8863d4bf23a7e0988"
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………………….. up several times in the night.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "woke",
                "have woken",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "631e0ecd24bc48ce844a035fdf798547"
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………………. to hear the news of his accident.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "was shocked",
                "have been shocked",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "5b321a7d8d9d431186db4b9e8725c4ee"
        },
        {
            "question": "They ……………………………. in July.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "got married",
                "have been gotten married",
                "were gotten"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "ddf9a5f2f47e49d3884762cc1da01d1e"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………… the whole of yesterday in bed.",
            "description": "We cannot use the present perfect tense with past time expressions.",
            "answers": [
                "spent",
                "have spent",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "9ea0bbdc08be461fb974ca68bdec04a0"
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………………. a lot of places on my last holiday.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "visited",
                "have visited",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "8705d3f850d64cfea6198deb57d7a320"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………… them for a long time.",
            "description": "The present perfect is used to talk about an action or situation that started in the past and has continued up to the present. ",
            "answers": [
                "knew",
                "have known",
                "was knowing"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "157e31729e344cc6bdb3cabf609c74ef"
        }
    ]
}